<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Webassembly on Flavio Castelli</title>
    <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/categories/webassembly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Webassembly on Flavio Castelli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://flavio.castelli.me/categories/webassembly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a unikernel that runs WebAssembly - part 1</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2023/02/07/building-a-unikernel-that-runs-webassembly---part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2023/02/07/building-a-unikernel-that-runs-webassembly---part-1/</guid>
      <description>Hackweek 22 took place last week. During this week all the SUSE employees are free to hack on whatever they want. This one of the perks of working at SUSE 😎.
This time my personal project has been about building a unikernel that runs WebAssembly.
 I wanted this blog post to contain all the details about this journey. However I realized this would have been too much for a single post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing with Common Expression Language</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2022/07/21/playing-with-common-expression-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2022/07/21/playing-with-common-expression-language/</guid>
      <description>Common Expression Language (CEL) is an expression language created by Google. It allows to define constraints that can be used to validate input data.
This language is being used by some open source projects and products, like:
 Google Cloud Certificate Authority Service Envoy There&amp;rsquo;s even a Kubernetes Enhancement Proposal that would use CEL to validate Kubernetes&amp;rsquo; CRDs.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at CEL since some time, wondering how hard it would be to find a way to write Kubewarden validation policies using this expression language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write kubectl plugins using WebAssembly and WASI</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2022/04/26/write-kubectl-plugins-using-webassembly-and-wasi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2022/04/26/write-kubectl-plugins-using-webassembly-and-wasi/</guid>
      <description>A long time passed since the last time I wrote something on this blog! 😅 I haven&amp;rsquo;t been idle during this time, quite the opposite&amp;hellip; I kept myself busy experimenting with WebAssembly and Kubernetes.
You probably have already heard about WebAssembly, but there are high chances that happened in the context of Web application development. There&amp;rsquo;s however a new emerging trend that consists of using WebAssembly outside of the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>