<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: kde | Flavio Castelli]]></title>
  <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/blog/categories/kde/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-13T17:40:40+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Flavio Castelli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[qjson 0.8.1 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2012/11/27/qjson-0-dot-8-1-released/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-27T11:24:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2012/11/27/qjson-0-dot-8-1-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick information, QJson 0.8.1 has been released. This release ensure API and ABI compatibility with version 0.7.1.</p>

<p>The previous 0.8.0 release broke ABI compatibility without changing the <code>SOVERSION</code>.</p>

<h2>Toward QJson 1.0.0</h2>

<p>I'm not entirely happy with some parts of QJson's API. I addressed these issues inside of the <a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson/tree/1_0_0">1_0_0</a> branch.</p>

<p>I would appreciate to hear your opinion before merging this branch into master and releasing QJson 1.0.0.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[QJson 0.8.0 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2012/11/21/qjson-0-dot-8-0-released/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T22:03:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2012/11/21/qjson-0-dot-8-0-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost three years passed since latest release of QJson.
A lot of stuff happened in my life and QJson definitely paid for that.
I have to admit I'm a bit ashamed.</p>

<p>So here we go, QJson 0.8.0 is out!</p>

<h2>What changed</h2>

<p>A lot of bugs has been smashed during this time, this new release will fix
issues like <a href="https://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=428256">this</a> one and
<a href="http://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=687537">this</a> in a nicer way.</p>

<p>QJson's API is still backward compatible, while the ABI changed.</p>

<h2>Symbian support</h2>

<p>Some work has also been done to get QJson work on the Symbian platform. The
development happened a long time before <a href="http://www.wired.com/business/2011/02/nokia-burning-platform/all/">Symbian was declared dead</a>.</p>

<p>Currently I do not offer any kind of support for the Symbian platform because
IMHO Symbian development is a mess and given the current situation in the mobile
world I don't see any point in investing more efforts on that.</p>

<p>Obviously Symbian patches and documentation are still accepted, as long as they
don't cause issues to the other target platforms.</p>

<h2>QMake support</h2>

<p>QJson always used cmake as build system but since some Windows developers
had problems with it I decided to add some <code>.pro</code> files. That proved to be a
bad choice for me since I had to support two build systems. I prefer to invest
my time fixing bugs in the code and adding interesting features rather then
triaging qmake issues on Windows. Hence I decided to remove them from git.</p>

<p>If you are a nostalgic you can still grab these files from git. They
have been removed with commit <a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson/commit/66d10c44dd3b21d693933f320c32b3c9a175a693">66d10c44dd3b21</a>.</p>

<h2>Relocating to Github</h2>

<p>I decided to move QJson's code from Gitorious to <a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson">Github</a>.
<a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson/issues">Github's issue sysyem</a> is going to replace Sourceforge's bug tracking system.</p>

<p>I currently use Github a lot, both for personal projects and for work, and I simply love it.
I think it offers the best tools in the market and that's really important to me.</p>

<p><a href="http://qjson.sourceforge.net">QJson's website</a> and mailing lists are still going to be hosted on Sourceforge.</p>

<hr>


<br>


<p>I think that's all from now. If you want more details about the changes introduced
take a look at the <a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson/blob/master/ChangeLog">changelog</a>
or checkout <a href="http://qjson.sourceforge.net">QJson's website</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
