<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: kde | Flavio Castelli]]></title>
  <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/blog/categories/kde/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/"/>
  <updated>2015-04-24T18:04:40+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Flavio Castelli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[qjson 0.8.1 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2012/11/27/qjson-0-dot-8-1-released/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-27T11:24:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2012/11/27/qjson-0-dot-8-1-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick information, QJson 0.8.1 has been released. This release ensure API and ABI compatibility with version 0.7.1.</p>

<p>The previous 0.8.0 release broke ABI compatibility without changing the <code>SOVERSION</code>.</p>

<h2>Toward QJson 1.0.0</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m not entirely happy with some parts of QJson&rsquo;s API. I addressed these issues inside of the <a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson/tree/1_0_0">1_0_0</a> branch.</p>

<p>I would appreciate to hear your opinion before merging this branch into master and releasing QJson 1.0.0.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[QJson 0.8.0 released]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2012/11/21/qjson-0-dot-8-0-released/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T22:03:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2012/11/21/qjson-0-dot-8-0-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost three years passed since latest release of QJson.
A lot of stuff happened in my life and QJson definitely paid for that.
I have to admit I&rsquo;m a bit ashamed.</p>

<p>So here we go, QJson 0.8.0 is out!</p>

<h2>What changed</h2>

<p>A lot of bugs has been smashed during this time, this new release will fix
issues like <a href="https://bugs.gentoo.org/show_bug.cgi?id=428256">this</a> one and
<a href="http://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=687537">this</a> in a nicer way.</p>

<p>QJson&rsquo;s API is still backward compatible, while the ABI changed.</p>

<h2>Symbian support</h2>

<p>Some work has also been done to get QJson work on the Symbian platform. The
development happened a long time before <a href="http://www.wired.com/business/2011/02/nokia-burning-platform/all/">Symbian was declared dead</a>.</p>

<p>Currently I do not offer any kind of support for the Symbian platform because
IMHO Symbian development is a mess and given the current situation in the mobile
world I don&rsquo;t see any point in investing more efforts on that.</p>

<p>Obviously Symbian patches and documentation are still accepted, as long as they
don&rsquo;t cause issues to the other target platforms.</p>

<h2>QMake support</h2>

<p>QJson always used cmake as build system but since some Windows developers
had problems with it I decided to add some <code>.pro</code> files. That proved to be a
bad choice for me since I had to support two build systems. I prefer to invest
my time fixing bugs in the code and adding interesting features rather then
triaging qmake issues on Windows. Hence I decided to remove them from git.</p>

<p>If you are a nostalgic you can still grab these files from git. They
have been removed with commit <a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson/commit/66d10c44dd3b21d693933f320c32b3c9a175a693">66d10c44dd3b21</a>.</p>

<h2>Relocating to Github</h2>

<p>I decided to move QJson&rsquo;s code from Gitorious to <a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson">Github</a>.
<a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson/issues">Github&rsquo;s issue sysyem</a> is going to replace Sourceforge&rsquo;s bug tracking system.</p>

<p>I currently use Github a lot, both for personal projects and for work, and I simply love it.
I think it offers the best tools in the market and that&rsquo;s really important to me.</p>

<p><a href="http://qjson.sourceforge.net">QJson&rsquo;s website</a> and mailing lists are still going to be hosted on Sourceforge.</p>

<hr>


<p><br>
I think that&rsquo;s all from now. If you want more details about the changes introduced
take a look at the <a href="https://github.com/flavio/qjson/blob/master/ChangeLog">changelog</a>
or checkout <a href="http://qjson.sourceforge.net">QJson&rsquo;s website</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast user switch plasmoid improvements]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2010/07/23/fast-user-switch-plasmoid-improvements/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-23T23:32:31+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2010/07/23/fast-user-switch-plasmoid-improvements</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just a quick note, I released a new version of the fastuserswitch plasmoid.
This new release implements all the improvements suggested by the users plus
some minor fixes.</p>

<p>Code can be downloaded from <a href="http://gitorious.org/fast_user_switch">here</a>.
openSUSE packages are already available on the <a href="http://software.opensuse.org/search?q=plasmoid-%0Afastuserswitch&amp;baseproject=ALL&amp;lang=en&amp;exclude_debug=true">build
service</a>.</p>

<p>These are some screenshots illustrating fastuserswitch&rsquo;s new features.</p>

<p><img src="/images/fast_user_switch/fastuserswitch011.png">
<img src="/images/fast_user_switch/fastuserswitch021.png">
<img src="/images/fast_user_switch/fastuserswitch03.png"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fast user switch plasmoid]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2010/07/15/fast-user-switch-plasmoid/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-15T07:23:11+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2010/07/15/fast-user-switch-plasmoid</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week my mother in law started to share her Linux laptop with my wife.
Suddenly my wife asked me how she could switch from one user session to
another. She was looking for something similar to <a href="http://bit.ly/auzc56">OS X fast user
switch</a> feature but she couldn&rsquo;t find it. In fact there
wasn&rsquo;t a fast and easy way to switch between users&#8217; sessions with KDE,
until&hellip; now :)</p>

<p>Let me introduce my first plasmoid: the fast user switch plasmoid. It&rsquo;s a
simple icon in the panel that allows users to swich to another open session or
to open a new login page. Here you can see the mandatory screenshots.</p>

<p><img src="/images/fast_user_switch/fastuserswitch02.png">
<img src="/images/fast_user_switch/fastuserswitch01.png"></p>

<p>You can find the source code
<a href="http://gitorious.org/fast_user_switch#more">here</a>. Binary packages for
openSUSE are already available on the <a href="http://software.opensuse.org/search?q=plasmoid-%0Afastuserswitch&amp;baseproject=ALL&amp;lang=en&amp;exclude_debug=true">build
service</a>.</p>

<h2>One last thought about KDM</h2>

<p>I think that KDM should allow to switch back to an already open session in a
more transparent way. Right now if an user has already one session open, he
goes back to the login screen and enters his credentials a <strong>new </strong> session is
started. I think that most users would expect to be switched back to their
already running session. Starting a new session is just confusing for them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[kaveau updates]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2009/09/14/kaveau-updates/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-14T23:38:54+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2009/09/14/kaveau-updates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some weeks have passed since the announcement of kaveau. I&rsquo;m really proud and
happy about this project because I received a lot of positive feedback
messages and it has been chosen as one of the best Hackweek&rsquo;s projects.</p>

<p>In the meantime I kept working on kaveau, so let me show you what has changed:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://rdiff-backup.nongnu.org/">rdiff-backup</a> has been replaced by <a href="http://www.samba.org/rsync/">rsync</a>.</li>
<li>the setup wizard has been improved according to the feedback messages I received.</li>
<li>old backups are now automatically removed.</li>
<li>the code has been refactored a lot.</li>
</ul>


<h3>The switch to rsync</h3>

<p>Previously kaveau used rdiff-backup as backup back-end. rdiff-backup is a
great program but unfortunately it relies on the outdated
<a href="http://librsync.sourceforge.net/">librsync</a> library. The latest release of
librsync is dated 2004. It has a couple of serious bugs still open and, while
rsync has reached version three, this library is still stuck at version one.</p>

<p>These are the reasons of the switch from rdiff-backup to rsync. This choice
breaks the compatibility with the previous backups but it introduces a lot of
advantages. One of the most important improvements brought by the adoption of
rsync is an easier restore procedure: now <strong>all</strong> the backups can be accessed
using a standard file manager, while previously rdiff-backup was needed to
access the old backups.</p>

<h4>Backup directory structure</h4>

<p>On the backup device everything is saved under the
<em>kaveau</em>/<em>hostname</em>/<em>username</em> path.</p>

<p>The directory will have a similar structure:</p>

<pre><code>drwxr-xr-x 3 flavio users 4096 2009-09-12 18:50 2009-09-12T18:50:19
drwxr-xr-x 3 flavio users 4096 2009-09-14 23:07 2009-09-14T23:07:46
drwxr-xr-x 3 flavio users 4096 2009-09-14 23:30 2009-09-14T23:30:36
lrwxrwxrwx 1 flavio users   19 2009-09-14 23:30 current -&gt; 2009-09-14T23:30:36
</code></pre>

<p>As you can see there&rsquo;s one directory per backup, plus a symlink called
<em>current</em> pointing to the latest backup.</p>

<h3>Old backup deletion</h3>

<p>Nowadays big external storage devices are pretty cheap, but it&rsquo;s always good
to save some disk space. Now kaveau keeps:</p>

<ul>
<li>hourly backups for the past 24 hours.</li>
<li>daily backups for the past month.</li>
<li>weekly backups until the external disk is full.
Thanks to hard links&#8217; magic, old backups can be deleted without causing
damages to the other ones.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Plans for the future</h3>

<p>Before starting to work on the restore user interface I will spend some time
figuring out how to add support for network devices.</p>

<p>A lot of users requested this feature, hence I want to make them happy :) .</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m planning to use <a href="http://avahi.org/">avahi</a> to discover network shares
(nfs, samba) or network machines running ssh and use them as backup devices.
Honestly, I want to achieve something similar to
<a href="http://www.apple.com/timecapsule/">Apple&rsquo;s time capsule</a>.</p>

<p>As usual, feedback messages are really appreciated.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
