<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Italy on Flavio Castelli</title>
    <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/categories/italy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Italy on Flavio Castelli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 12:37:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://flavio.castelli.me/categories/italy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Day 2007</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/10/29/linux-day-2007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 12:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/10/29/linux-day-2007/</guid>
      <description>Last Saturday Linux day 2007 took place.
Linux Day is an Italian manifestation that promotes Linux and FOSS. During this day different organizations (mostly Linux User Groups) arrange events with speeches, installation parties and more.
Since lot of people requested it, I gave a speech about KDE 4 during the Linux day organized by my LUG (BGLug).
The presentation covers the main changes and features introduced by KDE 4. I took inspiration from Troy&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Road to KDE 4&amp;rdquo; articles (I like them really much).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Desktop searching</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/06/05/desktop-searching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2007 14:22:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/06/05/desktop-searching/</guid>
      <description>An overview of desktop searching under linux.
This speech illustrates:
 what&amp;rsquo;s desktop searching what&amp;rsquo;re the benefits of desktop searching technology what&amp;rsquo;re the programs availables under linux overview of Beagle overview of Strigi  Desktop searchingView more presentations from Flavio Castelli. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE4 preview at Gazzaniga (BG)</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/05/29/kde4-preview-at-gazzaniga-bg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 12:38:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/05/29/kde4-preview-at-gazzaniga-bg/</guid>
      <description>A KDE 4 small overview This speech illustrates some of the major KDE4 features. Slides are shorts since has been made for a &amp;ldquo;wiki-night&amp;rdquo; :)
Kde4 previewView more presentations from Flavio Castelli. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Netiquette</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2006/10/28/netiquette/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2006 12:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2006/10/28/netiquette/</guid>
      <description>An introduction to netiquette. Revised version
This speech illustrates:
 what&amp;rsquo;s a mailing list and how does it works what&amp;rsquo;s a newsgroup what&amp;rsquo;s netiquette how to quote how to don&amp;rsquo;t break mailing lists threads  Netiquette v11View more presentations from Flavio Castelli. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regular expressions</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2006/09/12/regular-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2006 12:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2006/09/12/regular-expressions/</guid>
      <description>An introduction to Regular Expressions. This speech illustrates:
 regular expressions language main rules regexps with c++ (with boost library) regexps with python regexps with perl regexps with bash  Regular expressionsView more presentations from Flavio Castelli. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux on console</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2006/04/01/linux-on-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2006 12:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2006/04/01/linux-on-console/</guid>
      <description>These slides are about linux and modern console
The article focuses on the installation of linux over some modern console like:
 Sega Dreamcast™ Sony Playstation 2 ™ Microsoft Xbox™ The presentation focuses mostly on the Xbox™ case.  Linux consoleView more presentations from Flavio Castelli. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux and cryptography</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2005/08/12/linux-and-cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2005 12:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2005/08/12/linux-and-cryptography/</guid>
      <description>A speech about cryptography and linux.
This speech is about:
 crypted email with gnupg crypted file system avaible under linux, an overview and a comparison of loop-AES , cryptoloop, dm-crypt, bestcrypt creation of a full crypted file-system, root included. The most interesting feature is system&amp;rsquo;s boot sequence, which uses a usb token for authenticating users  Seminario crittografia-linux-day-2004View more presentations from Flavio Castelli. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>