<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | Flavio Castelli]]></title>
  <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-03T15:07:59+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Flavio Castelli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can dreams became true?]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2008/07/16/can-dreams-became-true/"/>
    <updated>2008-07-16T13:57:52+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2008/07/16/can-dreams-became-true</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the last years of university I spent some time wondering about my
future job. After the degree I received  lot of offers (fortunately also good
ones), but none of them matched with my <em>&ldquo;dream job&rdquo;</em> . There was always
something missing/different. I was just trying to convince myself that the
<em>&ldquo;perfect job&rdquo;</em> can exist only in our dreams when my feed reader pointed me
<a href="http://www.kdedevelopers.org/node/3484">here</a>.</p>

<p>After reading these lines:</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo; We are exploring new technologies, creating prototypes of future systems,
and trying to find and shape some of the features that will be part of
upcoming SUSE products and the ecosystem around that. It&rsquo;s a fascinating job,
challenging, fun, and always exciting. For somebody like me who loves to
create new things and enjoys working with an awesome team of innovative people
this is a dream job.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>

<p>I realized the description matched with all my wishes!</p>

<p>I immediately applied for the position and now, after more than a month, I&rsquo;m
looking at a signed proposal.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve waited a long time before spreading my joy to the rest of the world&hellip;
but now I just want to say that starting from 1st August I&rsquo;ll be part of
Suse&rsquo;s Incubation team! :D</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m really happy, excited and honoured for this awesome opportunity.</p>

<p><strong>I wish you&rsquo;ll be able to realize your dreams too!</strong><br/>
Just a funny note&hellip; While Cornelius was writing about the job offer on his
blog, I was having a dinner with another Novell employee:
<a href="http://primates.ximian.com/~massi/blog/">Massimiliano Mantione</a>. I was
listening to his personal story, wishing to find a dream job like his one.
I have to admit I was a bit jealous :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Two new entries in my life]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2008/03/26/two-new-entries-in-my-life/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-26T21:05:25+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2008/03/26/two-new-entries-in-my-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week two new entries entered my life.A shiny brand-new <em>Macbook pro
</em>arrived on Thursday. I&rsquo;ve always dreamed of one of this wonderful laptops
(I&rsquo;ve been an happy iBook user for a long time). Two weeks ago I finally
surrendered (I&rsquo;ve always been scared of the high price) and I&rsquo;ve ordered this
new <em>toy</em>. Now, after one week of usage I&rsquo;m really happy about it.</p>

<p>Currently I&rsquo;m using Linux as primary Os, but I&rsquo;ll give a try also to KDE4 on
Mac ;)</p>

<p>The other new entry is <em>Baguette</em>, a three-months old dachshund. She&rsquo;s really
lovely, running around the house eating random things like shoes (I think it&rsquo;s
a must for all pets) and usb cables (she&rsquo;s already a geek-dog).</p>

<p>I think I&rsquo;ll have to keep an eye on Baguette, otherwise I&rsquo;ll find another bite
on my Macbook pro apple ;)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xesam and bathroom hacking]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2007/08/10/xesam-and-bathroom-hacking/"/>
    <updated>2007-08-10T15:00:21+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2007/08/10/xesam-and-bathroom-hacking</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday morning I was quite arrived at work when Laura (my gf) called me.
Something went wrong in our bathroom and water was everywhere. She closed the
main water tap and I took the first train for home (yes, since I&rsquo;m an outlier
I take the train two times per day). Once arrived at home I performed some
hacking on the guilty washing machine, checked some pipes and than took the
next train for office.</p>

<p>In the end yesterday I spent approximately <strong>four hours</strong> on the train. During
this elapse of time I started the Xesam User Language parser :)  During the
travels I:</p>

<ul>
<li>refreshed my memories about <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/flex/">Flex</a>, <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/bison/">Bison</a> and language parsers in general</li>
<li>wrote XesamUserLanguage&rsquo;s <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Backus%E2%80%93Naur_form">BNF grammar</a></li>
<li>wrote Flex scanner</li>
<li>started Bison parser</li>
</ul>


<p>Now, after fixing some build errors, I&rsquo;ll start writing Bison&rsquo;s grammar rules.
These rules will translate Xesam user language queries into Strigi::Query
objects.</p>

<p>I hope it will work (both bathroom and Xesam parser ;) )</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New house opening]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2007/07/18/new-house-opening/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-18T10:47:46+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2007/07/18/new-house-opening</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last friday evening I made a party in my new house. We celebrated my birthday
and also the <em>&ldquo;opening&rdquo;</em> of the new house.</p>

<p>Many thanks to Roberto for the photos (made with his mobile phone!).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Work, work, work and... new house!]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2007/07/03/work-work-work-and-new-house/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-03T21:44:47+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2007/07/03/work-work-work-and-new-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my last message I promised to write some more contents on this site, in
order to keep it more updated. As usual I disappointed this promise :)  So,
what I have been doing in these day? Just a simple answer: I&rsquo;ve worked a lot.
&ldquo;Work&rdquo; can be divided in the following categories:</p>

<ul>
<li>office work</li>
<li>KDE &amp; Strigi coding</li>
<li>Physical work</li>
</ul>


<p>The most important of all is the last one. I&rsquo;ve spent all my week-ends working
in my <strong>new house</strong>. I&rsquo;ve been fixing and improving it (wow&hellip; it seems I&rsquo;m
talking about a piece of software ;) ) and now it&rsquo;s quite finished.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve to say a great <em>&ldquo;thank you&rdquo;</em> to my dad. He&rsquo;s able to do everything (he&rsquo;s
something better than <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MacGyver">Mac Gyver</a>) and
helped me a lot (in fact he has done all the dirty jobs).</p>

<p>Prepare yourself, I&rsquo;ll put some photos of the house really soon&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
