<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cloud | Flavio Castelli]]></title>
  <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/blog/categories/cloud/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-30T22:16:16+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Flavio Castelli]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building docker images with KIWI]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2014/05/06/building-docker-containers-with-kiwi/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-06T22:20:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2014/05/06/building-docker-containers-with-kiwi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m pleased to announce <a href="https://github.com/schaefi">Marcus Schäfer</a> has
just made possible to build docker images with <a href="http://opensuse.github.io/kiwi/">KIWI</a>.</p>

<p>For those who never heard about it, KIWI is a tool which creates Linux systems
for both physical and virtual machines. It can create openSUSE, SUSE and other types of
Linux distributions.</p>

<p><strong>Update:</strong> I changed the required version of kiwi and the openSUSE 13.1 template.
Kiwi just received some improvements which do no longer force the image
to include the <em>lxc</em> package.</p>

<h2>Why is this important?</h2>

<p>As you might know Docker has already its <a href="http://docs.docker.io/reference/builder/">build system</a>
which provides a really easy way to create new images. However these images
must be based on existing ones, which leads to the problem of creating the 1st
parent image. That&rsquo;s where KIWI comes to the rescue.</p>

<p>Indeed Kiwi can be used to build the openSUSE/SUSE/whatever docker images that are
going to act as the foundation blocks of other ones.</p>

<h2>Requirements</h2>

<p>Docker support has been added to KIWI 5.06.87. You can find this package inside
of the <a href="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show?project=Virtualization%3AAppliances">Virtualization:Appliances</a>
project on OBS.</p>

<p>Install the <code>kiwi</code> and the <code>kiwi-doc</code> packages on your system. Then go to the
<code>/usr/share/doc/packages/kiwi/examples/</code> directory where you will find a simple
openSUSE 13.1 template.</p>

<h2>Building the system</h2>

<p>Just copy the whole <code>/usr/share/doc/packages/kiwi/examples/suse-13.1/suse-docker-container</code>
directory to another location and make your changes.</p>

<p>The heart of the whole image is the <code>config.xml</code> file:</p>

<pre><code class="xml">&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?&gt;

&lt;image schemaversion="6.1" name="suse-13.1-docker-guest"&gt;
  &lt;description type="system"&gt;
    &lt;author&gt;Flavio Castelli&lt;/author&gt;
    &lt;contact&gt;fcastelli@suse.com&lt;/contact&gt;
    &lt;specification&gt;openSUSE 13.1 docker image&lt;/specification&gt;
  &lt;/description&gt;
  &lt;preferences&gt;
    &lt;type image="docker" container="os131"&gt;
      &lt;machine&gt;
        &lt;vmdisk/&gt;
        &lt;vmnic interface="eth0" mode="veth"/&gt;
      &lt;/machine&gt;
    &lt;/type&gt;
    &lt;version&gt;1.0.0&lt;/version&gt;
    &lt;packagemanager&gt;zypper&lt;/packagemanager&gt;
    &lt;rpm-check-signatures&gt;false&lt;/rpm-check-signatures&gt;
    &lt;rpm-force&gt;true&lt;/rpm-force&gt;
    &lt;locale&gt;en_US&lt;/locale&gt;
    &lt;keytable&gt;us.map.gz&lt;/keytable&gt;
    &lt;hwclock&gt;utc&lt;/hwclock&gt;
    &lt;timezone&gt;US/Eastern&lt;/timezone&gt;
  &lt;/preferences&gt;
  &lt;users group="root"&gt;
    &lt;user password="$1$wYJUgpM5$RXMMeASDc035eX.NbYWFl0" home="/root" name="root"/&gt;
  &lt;/users&gt;
  &lt;repository type="yast2"&gt;
    &lt;source path="opensuse://13.1/repo/oss/"/&gt;
  &lt;/repository&gt;
  &lt;packages type="image"&gt;
    &lt;package name="coreutils"/&gt;
    &lt;package name="iputils"/&gt;
  &lt;/packages&gt;
  &lt;packages type="bootstrap"&gt;
    &lt;package name="filesystem"/&gt;
    &lt;package name="glibc-locale"/&gt;
    &lt;package name="module-init-tools"/&gt;
  &lt;/packages&gt;
&lt;/image&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>This is a really minimal image which contains just a bunch of packages.</p>

<p>The first step is the creation of the image&rsquo;s root system:</p>

<pre><code>kiwi -p /usr/share/doc/packages/kiwi/examples/suse-13.1/suse-docker-container \
     --root /tmp/myimage
</code></pre>

<p>The next step compresses the file system of the image into a single tarball:</p>

<pre><code>    kiwi --create /tmp/myimage --type docker -d /tmp/myimage-result
</code></pre>

<p>The tarball can be found under <code>/tmp/myimage-result</code>. This can be imported
into docker using the following command:</p>

<pre><code>docker import - myImage &lt; /path/to/myimage.tbz
</code></pre>

<p>The image named <code>myImage</code> is now ready to be used.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next</h2>

<p>In the next days I&rsquo;ll make another blog post explaining how to build docker
images using KIWI and the <a href="http://openbuildservice.org/">Open Build Service</a>.
This is a powerful combination which allows to achieve continuous delivery.</p>

<p>Stay tuned and have fun!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Docker and openSUSE getting closer]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2014/02/13/docker-and-opensuse-getting-closer/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-13T10:46:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2014/02/13/docker-and-opensuse-getting-closer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have some good news about Docker and openSUSE.</p>

<p>First of all the Docker package has been moved from my personal OBS project
to the more official <a href="https://build.opensuse.org/package/show?project=Virtualization&amp;package=docker">Virtualization</a>
one. The next step is to get the Docker package into Factory :)</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m going to drop the <code>docker</code> package from <code>home:flavio_castelli:docker</code>,
so make sure to subscribe to the <code>Virtualization</code> repository to get latest versions of
Docker.</p>

<p>I have also submitted some openSUSE related documentation to the official Docker
project. If you visit the <a href="https://www.docker.io/gettingstarted/#h_installation">&ldquo;Getting started&rdquo;</a>
page you will notice the familiar geeko logo. Click it to be redirected to the
openSUSE&rsquo;s installation instructions.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Better Docker experience on openSUSE]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2013/11/28/better-docker-experience-on-opensuse/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-28T17:28:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2013/11/28/better-docker-experience-on-opensuse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&rsquo;t know if you are aware of that, but Docker 0.7.0 has been released a
couple of days ago.</p>

<p>You can read the full announcement <a href="http://blog.docker.io/2013/11/docker-0-7-docker-now-runs-on-any-linux-distribution/">here</a>,
but let me talk about the biggest change introduced by this release: storage drivers!</p>

<p>Docker has always used <a href="http://aufs.sourceforge.net/">AUFS</a>,
a &ldquo;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UnionFS">unionfs-like</a>&rdquo; file system, to power
its containers. Unfortunately AUFS is neither part of the official kernel nor
of the openSUSE/SLE one.</p>

<p><a href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2013/04/12/docker-and-opensuse/">In the past</a> I had
to build a custom patched kernel to run Docker on openSUSE. That proved to be
a real pain both for me and for the end users.</p>

<p>Now with storage drivers Docker can still use AUFS, but can also opt for something
different. In our case Docker is going to use <a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/465740/">thin provisioning</a>,
a consolidated technology which is part of the mainstream kernel since quite some time.</p>

<p>Moreover Docker&rsquo;s community is working on experimental drivers for BTRFS, ZFS,
Gluster and Ceph.</p>

<h2>What changes now for openSUSE?</h2>

<p>Running Docker is incredibly simple now: just use the <a href="http://software.opensuse.org/package/docker">1 click install</a>
and download it from the <em>&lsquo;home:flavio_castelli:docker&rsquo;</em> project.</p>

<p>As I said earlier: <strong>no custom kernel is required</strong>. You are going to keep the
one shipped by the official openSUSE repositories.</p>

<p>Just keep in mind that Docker does some initialization tasks on its very first
execution (it configures thin provisioning). So just wait a little before hitting its
API with the Docker cli tool (you will just get an error because <code>docker.socket</code>
is not found).</p>

<h2>The road ahead</h2>

<h3>Support SLE</h3>

<p>Right now Docker works fine on openSUSE 12.3 and 13.1 but not on SLE 11 SP3. During
the next days I&rsquo;m going to look into this issue. I want to have a stable and working
package for SLE.</p>

<h3>Make it more official</h3>

<p>Once the package is proved to be stable enough I&rsquo;ll submit it for inclusion inside
of the <a href="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show/Virtualization">Virtualization</a>
project on OBS.</p>

<p>So please, checkout Docker package  and provide me your feedback!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Docker and openSUSE: a container full of Geekos]]></title>
    <link href="http://flavio.castelli.name/2013/04/12/docker-and-opensuse/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-12T14:45:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://flavio.castelli.name/2013/04/12/docker-and-opensuse</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://hackweek.suse.com/">SUSE&rsquo;s Hackweek #9</a> is over. It has
been an awesome week during which I worked hard to make <a href="http://www.docker.io">docker</a>
a first class citizen on <a href="http://www.opensuse.org/">openSUSE</a>. I also spent
some time working on an openSUSE container that could be used by docker&rsquo;s users.</p>

<p>The project has been tracked on <a href="https://github.com/SUSE/hackweek/wiki/docker.io-and-openSUSE">this</a>
page of hackweek&rsquo;s wiki, this is a detailed report of what I achieved.</p>

<h2>Installing docker on openSUSE 12.3</h2>

<p>Docker has been packaged inside of <a href="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show?project=home%3Aflavio_castelli%3Adocker">this</a>
OBS project.</p>

<p>So installing it requires just two commands:</p>

<pre><code>sudo zypper ar http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/home:/flavio_castelli:/docker/openSUSE_12.3 docker
sudo zypper in docker
</code></pre>

<p>There&rsquo;s also a <a href="http://software.opensuse.org/ymp/home:flavio_castelli:docker/openSUSE_12.3/docker.ymp?base=openSUSE%3A12.3&amp;query=docker">1 Click Install</a>
for the lazy ones :)</p>

<p>Zypper will install docker and its dependencies which are:</p>

<ul>
<li><code>lxc</code>: docker&rsquo;s &ldquo;magic&rdquo; is built on top of <a href="http://lxc.sourceforge.net/">LXC</a>.</li>
<li><code>bridge-utils</code>: is used to setup the bridge interface used by docker&rsquo;s
containers.</li>
<li><code>dnsmasq</code>: is used to start the dhcp server used by the containers.</li>
<li><code>iptables</code>: is used to get containers&#8217; networking work.</li>
<li><code>bsdtar</code>: is used by docker to compress/extract the containers.</li>
<li><a href="http://aufs.sourceforge.net/">aufs3</a> kernel module: is used by docker to
track the changes made to the containers.</li>
</ul>


<p>The <code>aufs3</code> kernel module is <strong>not</strong> part of the official kernel and is <strong>not</strong>
available on the official repositories. Hence adding docker will trigger the
<strong>installation of a new kernel package</strong> on your machine.</p>

<p>Both the kernel and the aufs3 packages are going to be installed from the
<em>home:flavio_castelli:docker</em> repository but they
are in fact links to the packages created by <a href="https://build.opensuse.org/home?user=-miska-">Michal Hrusecky</a>
inside of his <a href="https://build.opensuse.org/package/show?package=aufs3&amp;project=home%3A-miska-%3Aaufs">aufs project</a>
on OBS.</p>

<p><strong>Note well:</strong> docker works only on 64bit hosts. That&rsquo;s why there are no 32bit
packages.</p>

<h2>Docker appliance</h2>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t want to install docker on your system or you are just curious and
want to jump straight into action there&rsquo;s a <a href="http://susestudio.com">SUSE Studio</a>
appliance ready for you. You can find it <a href="http://susestudio.com/a/CZ0T0D/docker">here</a>.</p>

<p>If you are not familiar with SUSE Gallery let me tell you two things about it:</p>

<ul>
<li>you can download the appliance on your computer and play with it or&hellip;</li>
<li>you can clone the appliance on SUSE Studio and customize it even further or&hellip;</li>
<li>you can test the appliance from your browser using SUSE Studio&rsquo;s Testdrive
feature (no SUSE Studio account required!).</li>
</ul>


<p>The latter option is really cool, because it will allow you to play with docker
immediately. There&rsquo;s just one thing to keep in mind about Testdrive: outgoing
connections are disabled, so you won&rsquo;t be able to install new stuff (or download
new docker images). Fortunately this appliance comes with the busybox container
bundled, so you will be able to play a bit with docker.</p>

<h2>Running docker</h2>

<p>The docker daemon must be running in order to use your containers. The openSUSE
package comes with a init script which can be used to manage it.</p>

<p>The script is <code>/etc/init.d/docker</code>, but there&rsquo;s also the usual symbolic link
called <code>/usr/sbin/rcdocker</code>.</p>

<p>To start the docker daemon just type:
<code>
sudo /usr/sbin/rcdocker start
</code></p>

<p>This will trigger the following actions:</p>

<ol>
<li> The <code>docker0</code> bridge interface is created. This interface is bridged
 with <code>eth0</code>.</li>
<li> A <code>dnsmasq</code> instance listening on the <code>docker0</code> interface is started.</li>
<li> IP forwarding and IP masquerading are enabled.</li>
<li> Docker daemon is started.</li>
</ol>


<p>All the containers will get an IP on the <code>10.0.3.0/24</code> network.</p>

<h2>Playing with docker</h2>

<p>Now is time to play with docker.</p>

<p>First of all you need to download an image: <code>docker pull base</code></p>

<p>This will fetch the official Ubuntu-based image created by the
<a href="http://www.dotcloud.com/">dotCloud</a> guys.</p>

<p>You will be able to run the Ubuntu container on your openSUSE host without any
problem, that&rsquo;s LXC&rsquo;s &ldquo;magic&rdquo; ;)</p>

<p>If you want to use only &ldquo;green&rdquo; products just pull the openSUSE 12.3 container
I created for you:
<code>
docker pull flavio/opensuse-12-3
</code></p>

<p>Please <strong>experiment a lot with this image</strong> and <strong>give me your feedback</strong>.
The dotCloud guys proposed me to promote it to top-level base image, but I want
to be sure everything works fine before doing that.</p>

<p>Now you can go through the <a href="http://docs.docker.io/en/latest/examples/running_examples/">examples</a>
reported on the official
<a href="http://docs.docker.io/en/latest/concepts/containers/">docker&rsquo;s documentation</a>.</p>

<h2>Create your own openSUSE images with SUSE Studio</h2>

<p>I think it would be extremely cool to create docker&rsquo;s images using
<a href="http://susestudio.com">SUSE Studio</a>.
As you might know I&rsquo;m part of the SUSE Studio team, so I looked a bit into how
to add support to this new format.</p>

<p><strong>&ndash; personal opinion &ndash;</strong></p>

<p>There are some technical challenges to solve, but I don&rsquo;t think it would be hard
to address them.</p>

<p><strong>&ndash; personal opinion &ndash;</strong></p>

<p>If you are interested in adding the docker format to SUSE Studio please create
a new feature request on <a href="https://features.opensuse.org/">openFATE</a> and vote it!</p>

<p>In the meantime there&rsquo;s another way to create your custom docker images, just
keep reading.</p>

<h2>Create your own openSUSE images with KIWI</h2>

<p><a href="http://opensuse.github.io/kiwi">KIWI</a> is the amazing tool at the heart of
SUSE Studio and can be used to create LXC containers.</p>

<p>As said earlier docker runs LXC containers, so we are going to follow
<a href="http://doc.opensuse.org/projects/kiwi/doc/#sec.lxc.building">these</a> instructions.</p>

<p>First of all install KIWI from the <a href="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show?project=Virtualization%3AAppliances">Virtualization:Appliances</a> project on OBS:
<code>
sudo zypper ar http://download.opensuse.org/repositories/Virtualization:/Appliances/openSUSE_12.3 virtualization:appliances
sudo zypper in kiwi kiwi-doc
</code></p>

<p>We are going to use the configuration files of a simple LXC container shipped
the <code>kiwi-doc</code> package:
<code>
cp -r /usr/share/doc/packages/kiwi/examples/suse-11.3/suse-lxc-guest ~/openSUSE_12_3_docker
</code></p>

<p>The <code>openSUSE_12_3_docker</code> directory contains two configuration files used by
KIWI (<code>config.sh</code> and <code>config.xml</code>) plus the <code>root</code> directory.</p>

<p>The contents of this directory are going to be added to the resulting container.
It&rsquo;s really important to create the <code>/etc/resolv.conf</code> file inside of the
final image since docker is going to mount the <code>resol.conf</code> file of the host
system inside of the running guest. If the file is not found docker won&rsquo;t be able
to start our container.</p>

<p>An empty file is enough:
<code>
touch ~/openSUSE_12_3_docker/root/etc/resolv.conf
</code></p>

<p>Now we can create the rootfs of the container using KIWI:
<code>
sudo /usr/sbin/kiwi --prepare ~/openSUSE_12_3_docker --root /tmp/openSUSE_12_3_docker_rootfs
</code></p>

<p>We can skip the next step reported on KIWI&rsquo;s documentation, that&rsquo;s not needed
with docker because it will produce an invalid container. Just execute the
following command:
<code>
sudo tar cvjpf openSUSE_12_3_docker.tar.bz2 -C /tmp/openSUSE_12_3_docker_rootfs/ .
</code></p>

<p>This will produce a tarball containing the rootfs of your container.</p>

<p>Now you can import it inside of docker, there are two ways to achieve that:</p>

<ul>
<li>from a web server.</li>
<li>from a local file.</li>
</ul>


<p>Importing the image from a web server is really convenient if you ran KIWI
on a different machine.</p>

<p>Just move the tarball to a directory which is exposed by the web server. If you don&rsquo;t
have one installed just move to the directory containing the tarball and type the following
command:
<code>
python -m SimpleHTTPServer 8080
</code>
This will start a simple http server listening on port 8080 of your machine.</p>

<p>On the machine running docker just type:
<code>
docker import http://mywebserver/openSUSE_12_3_docker.tar.bz2 my_openSUSE_image latest
</code></p>

<p>If the tarball is already on the machine running docker you just need to type:
<code>
cat ~/openSUSE_12_3_docker.tar.bz2 | docker import - my_openSUSE_image latest
</code></p>

<p>Docker will download (just in the 1st case) and import the tarball. The resulting
image will be named <em>&lsquo;my_openSUSE_image&rsquo;</em> and it will have a tag named <em>&lsquo;latest&rsquo;</em>.</p>

<p>The name of the tag is really important since docker tries to run the
image with the <em>&lsquo;latest&rsquo;</em> tag unless you explicitly specify a different value.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Hackweek #9 has been both productive and fun for me. I hope you will have fun
too using docker on openSUSE.</p>

<p>As usual, feedback is welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
