<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Flavio Castelli</title>
    <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Flavio Castelli</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 13:57:52 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://flavio.castelli.me/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Can dreams became true?</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2008/07/16/can-dreams-became-true/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 13:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2008/07/16/can-dreams-became-true/</guid>
      <description>During the last years of university I spent some time wondering about my future job. After the degree I received lot of offers (fortunately also good ones), but none of them matched with my &amp;ldquo;dream job&amp;rdquo; . There was always something missing/different. I was just trying to convince myself that the &amp;ldquo;perfect job&amp;rdquo; can exist only in our dreams when my feed reader pointed me here.
After reading these lines:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two new entries in my life</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2008/03/26/two-new-entries-in-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 21:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2008/03/26/two-new-entries-in-my-life/</guid>
      <description>Last week two new entries entered my life.A shiny brand-new _Macbook pro _arrived on Thursday. I&amp;rsquo;ve always dreamed of one of this wonderful laptops (I&amp;rsquo;ve been an happy iBook user for a long time). Two weeks ago I finally surrendered (I&amp;rsquo;ve always been scared of the high price) and I&amp;rsquo;ve ordered this new toy. Now, after one week of usage I&amp;rsquo;m really happy about it.
Currently I&amp;rsquo;m using Linux as primary Os, but I&amp;rsquo;ll give a try also to KDE4 on Mac ;)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xesam and bathroom hacking</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/08/10/xesam-and-bathroom-hacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2007 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/08/10/xesam-and-bathroom-hacking/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday morning I was quite arrived at work when Laura (my gf) called me. Something went wrong in our bathroom and water was everywhere. She closed the main water tap and I took the first train for home (yes, since I&amp;rsquo;m an outlier I take the train two times per day). Once arrived at home I performed some hacking on the guilty washing machine, checked some pipes and than took the next train for office.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New house opening</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/07/18/new-house-opening/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2007 10:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/07/18/new-house-opening/</guid>
      <description>Last friday evening I made a party in my new house. We celebrated my birthday and also the &amp;ldquo;opening&amp;rdquo; of the new house.
Many thanks to Roberto for the photos (made with his mobile phone!).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work, work, work and... new house!</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/07/03/work-work-work-and...-new-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 21:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/07/03/work-work-work-and...-new-house/</guid>
      <description>In my last message I promised to write some more contents on this site, in order to keep it more updated. As usual I disappointed this promise :) So, what I have been doing in these day? Just a simple answer: I&amp;rsquo;ve worked a lot. &amp;ldquo;Work&amp;rdquo; can be divided in the following categories:
 office work KDE &amp;amp; Strigi coding Physical work   The most important of all is the last one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dot.kde.org and me</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/05/10/dot.kde.org-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2007 19:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/05/10/dot.kde.org-and-me/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really honored to report that dot.kde.org has published the english translation of my interview for kde-it. You can find it here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE Italy and me</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/05/07/kde-italy-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 19:32:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/05/07/kde-italy-and-me/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really honored to report that KDE-Italy site published an interview about me. You can find it here. Many thanks to Giovanni Venturi, webmaster and maintainer of kde-it.org!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back from FOSDEM</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/03/01/back-from-fosdem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 19:06:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/03/01/back-from-fosdem/</guid>
      <description>A small resume of my FOSDEM experience&amp;hellip;
Friday evening Departure from Italy. The plane landed in Charlesroi airport, where we (me and Laura) take a bus for Bruxelles. Once in the city it was so late that there was no public transport, so we had to take a cab in order to reach our hotel.
Saturday Small tour in Bruxelles. As we thought Bruxelles is a beautiful city with lot of things to see, in fact there are too many things to see for a 2 day trip!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going to FOSDEM 2007 edition</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/02/17/going-to-fosdem-2007-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2007 20:11:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/02/17/going-to-fosdem-2007-edition/</guid>
      <description>This year I&amp;rsquo;ll go to FOSDEM 2007 edition where I&amp;rsquo;ll give a presentation regarding Strigi.
FOSDEM stands for &amp;ldquo;Free Open Source Developers European Meeting&amp;rdquo;.
This is one of the most important happenings for the open-source scene in Europe. It takes place in Bruxelles, where for two days the university if full of talks, and stands of open-source projects.
Big projects have a DevRoom, a place reserved for talks related with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still alive</title>
      <link>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/02/17/still-alive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2007 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://flavio.castelli.me/2007/02/17/still-alive/</guid>
      <description>As usually lot of time passed since my last post on this site. Hundred of things happened in the meantime&amp;hellip; Going in order:
 I took my second level degree in Computer Engineering I began to work in a IT company I&amp;rsquo;m going to give a presentation of strigi to fosdem It&amp;rsquo;s really hard (and honestly I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough time) to give a detailed resume of all these facts. The graduation went really fine, my teacher and the other one in the examining session liked my work and I got a good score.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>